

SARAH PAO

Multidisciplinary UX Designer

sarahpja@gmail.com | 650-862-8849

Summary

UX designer with a background in mechanical engineering. Brings 5+ years of experience specializing in customer centric research, design, and problem solving. Passionate about developing engaging experiences in the digital and physical space for all

Skills

- User research and usability testing
- Information architecture
- Technical communication
- Prototyping, wireframing, user flow
- Visual design in Figma, Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator
- Basic understanding of HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Experience

Customer Service Associate

07/2021 - 01/2023

Lowe's Home Improvement | Syracuse, NY

- Addressed inquiries, resolved customer issues, and managed customer relations.
- Prioritized the safety of coworkers and shoppers by communicating with managers regarding repeated safety nonconformances
- Trained 7 new hires on products and services, best practices and procedures to reduce operational shrink.
- Recommended and initiated product offerings to meet customer's changing needs.

Associate Mechanical Engineer

07/2017 - 09/2019

Carrier Corporation | Syracuse, NY Sustaining Engineer

- Analyzed sales data to understand customer needs and teamed up with field engineers to address customer questions and complaints
- Supported manufacturing team with production problems
- Investigated high-failure products for root causes and worked with both internal and external groups toward a solution

New product development

 Conducted simulation to evaluate system performance and capacity to meet 2023 requirements

Research Assistant 02/2013 - 05/2017

Rochester Institute of Technology, RIT | Rochester, NY

- Researched in mechanical properties of polylactic acid (PLA) blends for packaging applications
- Designed experiments and developed processes for producing and testing samples on 4 pieces of equipment
- Organized, analyzed, and presented data to aid the decision-making process

- Trained new assistants on various test equipment
- Produced extrusion-blown films and 3D printing filaments from custom formula PLA blends for 3 research groups

Projects

Non-profit Organization Webpage Redesign

Alley Cat Allies

- Redesigned the layout and reorganized content on the Take Action landing page to show relevant information at the top of the page.
- Added a clear Call To Action (CTA) to the page.
- Updated the site with minimalist style to decrease the user's cognitive load.

Government Agency Homepage Redesign

US Department of Education

- Updated the department of education's website homepage for a more modern look.
- Eliminated multiple side navigation menus by introducing hierarchy to the main navigation and content.

Mobile App Design

JED is a platform that focuses on building trust between the seller and customers. Customers have access to detailed information on the product and a cost breakdown of each item they purchased. Information about the sellers is easy to find and customers can also support them with donations.

- Created a mobile app to solve common problems online shoppers and small business owners face.
- Identified user problems, brainstormed solutions, and created prototypes for testing.

Education and Training

Certificate: UX/UI Design

University of Minnesota - Twin Cities | Minneapolis, MN

Bachelor of Science: Mechanical Engineering Technology

Rochester Institute of Technology | Rochester, NY

- 3.94 GPA
- Graduated summa cum laude
- Outstanding Undergraduate Scholar Award Recipient

Portfolios and Profiles

- https://sarahpja.github.io/PortfolioSite/index.html
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/sarahlpao/

11/2022

06/2017